Guide to the Wilmarth Sheldon Lewis Papers
The Lewis Walpole Library
- Correspondence, 1901–1979; Series I; 76.56; 181 boxes
  - General Correspondence
    - St. Mary's College (Twickenham, London, England), 1932–1979 (Box 117, Folder 11)
    - Sale, Robert C., 1959–1960 (Box 117, Folder 12)
    - Saltmarsh, John, 1908-1974, 1936–1939 (Box 117, Folder 13)
    - Sammons, Jeffrey L. and Harold L., 1956–1959 (Box 117, Folder 14)
    - Sands, Joan, 1973–1979 (Box 117, Folder 15)
    - Sandwich, George Charles, 9th Earl of, 1939 (Box 117, Folder 16)
    - Sardeson, Hope, 1975–1978 (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - Sass, Lorna J., 1977 (Box 118, Folder 2)
    - Sassoon, Sybil, 1894-1989, 1949–1975 (Box 118, Folder 3-4)
    - Sawbridge, Margaret, 1974 (Box 118, Folder 5)
    - Sawyer, Charles H., 1946–1969 (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - Scarecrow Press, 1975 (Box 118, Folder 7)
    - Scarfe, Norman, 1976–1977 (Box 118, Folder 8)
    - Scarth, Helen M., 1947–1965 (Box 118, Folder 9)
    - Schatten, Richard and Monique, 1969–1979 (Box 118, Folder 10)
    - Schatzki, Walter, 1899-1983, 1947–1976 (Box 118, Folder 11)
    - Scheideman, Warren, 1968–1972 (Box 118, Folder 12)
    - Scheyven, Louis, Baron, 1964 (Box 118, Folder 13)
    - Schiff, John M., 1957–1966 (Box 118, Folder 14)
    - Schindler's Antique Shop, 1952–1959 (Box 118, Folder 15)
    - Schley, Reeve and Kate Prentice, 1939–1970 (Box 118, Folder 16)
    - Schlossberg, Suzanne, 1977 (Box 118, Folder 17)
    - Schoefield, Bertha, 1953 (Box 118, Folder 18)
    - Schroeder, John C., 1946–1954 (Box 118, Folder 19)
    - Scolar Press, 1972–1978 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Scott, Ernest, 1950–1951 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - Scott & Fowles (Firm), 1947–1950 (Box 119, Folder 3)
    - Scottish National Portrait Gallery, 1970–1979 (Box 119, Folder 4)
    - Scottish Record Office, 1968–1970 (Box 119, Folder 5)
    - Scoville, Samuel, 1872-, 1939–1940 (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Scribner Book Store, 1946–1977 (Box 119, Folder 7)
    - Scruggs, Charles, 1974 (Box 119, Folder 8)
    - Seabury, Mortimer, 1940 (Box 119, Folder 9)
    - Sedgwick, Ellery, 1872-1960, and Marjorie, 1951–1969 (Box 119, Folder 10)
    - Sedgwick, Romney, 1894-, and Mana Hodson, 1956–1978 (Box 119, Folder 11)
    - Seljouk, M. A. (Mehdi Ali), 1935-, 1964–1978 (Box 119, Folder 12)
    - Sellers, Charles Coleman, 1903-1980, 1959–1971 (Box 119, Folder 13)
    - Senhouse, Roger, 1948–1950 (Box 119, Folder 14)
    - Seven Gables Bookshop, 1940–1979 (Box 119, Folder 15-17)
    - Sexton, Eric, 1951–1955 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - Seymour, Charles, 1885-1963, 1932–1960 (Box 120, Folder 2-3)
    - Seymour, George Dudley, 1859-1945, 1930–1939 (Box 120, Folder 4)
    - Seymour, Horatia, 1935 (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - Sharp, Janet Ritchie, 1964–1979 (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - Shatto, Mary J., 1961 (Box 120, Folder 7)
    - Sheffield, Frederick, 1946–1964 (Box 120, Folder 8)
    - Shelbourne Hotel, 1955–1962 (Box 120, Folder 9)
    - Shenker, Israel, 1973–1979 (Box 120, Folder 10)
    - Shepard, Frank P., 1947–1953 (Box 120, Folder 11)
    - Shepardson, Whitney H. (Whitney Hart), 1890-1966, 1946–1965 (Box 120, Folder 12)
    - Shepley, Ethan A. H. (Ethan Allen Hitchcock), 1896-1975, 1946–1963 (Box 121, Folder 1)
    - Shepperson, Archibald Bolling, 1897-1962, 1949–1961 (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Shera, Jesse Hauk, 1903-1982, 1943–1979 (Box 121, Folder 3)
    - Sherburn, George, 1884-1962, 1934–1956 (Box 121, Folder 4)
    - Sherman, Frederick Barreda, 1892-, 1939–1977 (Box 121, Folder 5)
    - Sherrill, Henry Knox, 1890-1980, 1937–1980 (Box 121, Folder 6)
    - Shipley, John B., 1955–1978 (Box 121, Folder 7)
    - Shirren, A. J., 1947 (Box 121, Folder 8)
    - Shivers, Frank, 1949 (Box 121, Folder 9)
    - Shortall, Harrington, 1895-1984, 1936–1979 (Box 122, Folder 1-2)
    - Schutze, Philip Trammell, 1973–1974 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - Sieveking, Lance, 1896-1972, 1946–1957 (Box 122, Folder 4)
    - Silver, Louis H., 1955 (Box 122, Folder 5)
    - Simcox, Richard, 1951–1958 (Box 122, Folder 6)
    - Simmons, J. S. G. (John Simon Gabriel), 1915-2005, 1968–1969 (Box 122, Folder 7)
    - Simon, Eric M., 1892-1978, 1945–1952 (Box 122, Folder 8)
    - Simon Fraser University, 1969 (Box 122, Folder 9)
    - Simonds, Bruce, 1953–1975 (Box 122, Folder 10)
    - Simonson, Lee, 1888-1967, 1940 (Box 122, Folder 11)
    - Sinnott, Edmund W. (Edmund Ware), 1888-1958, 1944–1963 (Box 122, Folder 12)
    - Sir John Soane's Museum, 1935–1969 (Box 122, Folder 13)
    - Sitwell, Osbert, 1892-1969, and Edith, 1949–1961 (Box 122, Folder 14)
    - Sizer, Theodore, 1892-1967, 1932–1966 (Box 122, Folder 15-16)
    - Skilton, John D. (John Davis), 1909-1992, 1973 (Box 123, Folder 1)
    - Smallwood, Frank T., 1890-1982, 1970–1971 (Box 123, Folder 2)
    - Smart, Alastair, 1922-, 1967–1970 (Box 123, Folder 3)
    - Smart, Jeffrey, 1921-2013, 1967–1969 (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - Smith, Audrey, 1953–1978 (Box 123, Folder 5)
    - Smith, Charles D., 1958–1977 (Box 123, Folder 6)
    - Smith College, 1946–1954 (Box 123, Folder 7)
    - Smith College. Museum of Art, 1946–1961 (Box 123, Folder 8)
    - Smith, David Nichol, 1875-1962, 1931–1962 (Box 123, Folder 9)
    - Smith, Glanville, 1945–1951 (Box 123, Folder 10)
    - Smith, Harrison, 1938–1942 (Box 123, Folder 11)
    - Smith, Hayden N., 1948 (Box 123, Folder 12)
    - Smith, Lucille B., 1957–1961 (Box 123, Folder 13)
    - Smith, Olcott Damon, 1969–1974 (Box 123, Folder 14)
    - Smith, Osbert W. D., 1958 (Box 123, Folder 15)
    - Smith, Robert A., 1949–1968 (Box 123, Folder 16-17)
    - Smith, Roger William, 1958–1970 (Box 123, Folder 18)
    - Smith, Sally Conklin, 1969–1975 (Box 123, Folder 19)
    - Smith, Warren Hunting, 1905-1998, 1935–1953 (Box 124, Folder 1-6)
    - Smith, Warren Hunting, 1905-1998, 1954–1966 (Box 125, Folder 1-5)
    - Smith, Warren Hunting, 1905-1998, 1967–1979 (Box 126, Folder 1-5)
    - Smith, Winchell, 1871-1933, 1932, undated (Box 127, Folder 1)
    - Smithsonian Magazine, 1979 (Box 127, Folder 2)
    - Soby, James Thrall, 1906-1979, 1941–1967 (Box 127, Folder 3)
    - Society of Antiquaries of London, 1935–1979 (Box 127, Folder 4)
    - Society of Colonial Wars, 1944–1974 (Box 127, Folder 5)
    - Society of the Cincinnati, 1963–1966 (Box 127, Folder 6)
    - Société jersiaise, 1975–1978 (Box 127, Folder 7)
    - Solicitor's Law Stationery Society, Ltd., 1965–1968 (Box 127, Folder 8)
    - Solkin, David H., 1974–1976 (Box 127, Folder 9)
    - Somerset House (Teaneck, N.J.), 1978 (Box 127, Folder 10)
    - Sonnenberg, Benjamin, 1901-1978, 1969 (Box 127, Folder 11)
    - Sorensen, Henry, 1958–1979 (Box 127, Folder 12)
    - Sotheby's (Firm), 1937–1967 (Box 127, Folder 13-14)
    - Sotheby's (Firm), 1968–1978 (Box 128, Folder 1)
    - Southern Illinois University Press, 1962–1970 (Box 128, Folder 2)
    - Sparrow, John, 1906-1992, 1944–1969 (Box 128, Folder 3)
    - Spear, John A., 1950–1951 (Box 128, Folder 4)
    - Spence, Homer R., 1963–1973 (Box 128, Folder 5)
    - Spencer, T. J. B. (Terence John Bew), 1915-1978, 1960 (Box 128, Folder 6)
    - Spender, Percy, 1897-1985, 1972 (Box 128, Folder 7)
    - Spiegel, Eileen, 1955 (Box 128, Folder 8)
    - Spillane, Richard J., 1977–1979 (Box 128, Folder 9)
    - Spink, C. Marshall, 1948–1955 (Box 128, Folder 10)
    - Spink & Son, 1947–1960 (Box 128, Folder 11)
    - Spirito, Mary, 1952 (Box 128, Folder 12)
    - Spofford, Charles Merville, 1902-1991, 1959–1964 (Box 128, Folder 13)
    - Staake, William W., 1951 (Box 128, Folder 14)
    - Stafford Hotel, 1971–1974 (Box 128, Folder 15)
    - Stanton, Madeline E. (Madeline Earle), 1948–1973 (Box 128, Folder 16)
    - Starkey, George and Bisi, 1973–1975 (Box 128, Folder 17)
    - Starr, Herbert W. (Herbert Willmarth), 1916-, 1955–1969 (Box 128, Folder 18)
    - Stechert-Hafner, Inc., 1960 (Box 128, Folder 19)
    - Stedelijke Musea Brugge, 1967–1968 (Box 128, Folder 20)
    - Steegman, John, 1899-1966, 1949–1959 (Box 128, Folder 21)
    - Steers, Hugh Auchincloss, 1965–1970 (Box 128, Folder 22)
    - Steers, Newton I. (Newton Ivan), 1917-, 1956–1974 (Box 128, Folder 23)
    - Steiner, Louise, 1971 (Box 129, Folder 1)
      Contains correspondence, invitation lists, and tribute book from a party held for Louise Steiner and Grace M. Foster on June 20, 1971.
    - Stephens, Anthony W., 1967–1979 (Box 129, Folder 2)
    - Stephens, Lee and Bessie Beers, 1951–1965 (Box 129, Folder 3)
    - Stephens, William Barclay, 1952–1961 (Box 129, Folder 4)
    - Stephenson, Emma H.E., 1956–1965 (Box 129, Folder 5)
    - Stern, Philip M., 1961–1967 (Box 129, Folder 6)
    - Stevens, George, 1971–1972 (Box 129, Folder 7)
    - Stevens, James H. and Fran, 1972–1975 (Box 129, Folder 8)
    - Stevens, Robert B., 1964–1973 (Box 129, Folder 9)
    - Stevenson, Henry, 1969–1970 (Box 129, Folder 10)
    - Stewart, John P. and Ava, 1955–1968 (Box 129, Folder 11)
    - Stewart, George, 1939–1943 (Box 129, Folder 12)
    - Stiebel, Gerald G., 1971–1972 (Box 129, Folder 13)
    - Stillman, George Schley, 1940–1951 (Box 129, Folder 14)
    - Stinehour, Roderick, 1973 (Box 130, Folder 1)
    - Stockwell, Richard M. and Beatrice, 1962 (Box 130, Folder 2)
    - Stoddard, Carlos F., 1946–1969 (Box 130, Folder 3)
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1874-1958, 1934–1956 (Box 130, Folder 4)
    - Stone, Charles P. and Lee, 1952–1979 (Box 130, Folder 5)
    - Storm, Colton, 1908-1988, 1936–1961 (Box 130, Folder 6)
    - Stout, A. Varick, Jr., 1947–1953 (Box 130, Folder 7)
    - Straight, Nina A., 1954–1977 (Box 130, Folder 8)
    - Strawberry-Hill Press Inc., 1936–1952 (Box 130, Folder 9)
    - Street, Julian, 1879-1947 and Margot, 1946–1959 (Box 130, Folder 10)
    - Street, Kenneth Whistler, 1947–1955 (Box 130, Folder 11)
    - Streeter, Alice, 1949–1966 (Box 130, Folder 12)
    - Streeter, Edward Clark, -1947, 1937–1974 (Box 130, Folder 13)
    - Streeter, Thomas W. (Thomas Winthrop), 1883-1965, 1943–1965 (Box 130, Folder 14)
    - Strouse, Norman H., 1971–1979 (Box 130, Folder 15)
    - Stuart, Dorothy M., 1933–1962 (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Studies in Burke and His Time, 1973–1974 (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - Sturdy, Herbert F., 1952–1962 (Box 131, Folder 3)
    - Suckling and Co., 1925–1971 (Box 131, Folder 4)
    - Suffolk Record Office. Bury St. Edmund Branch, 1953–1968 (Box 131, Folder 5)
    - Sullivan, William G. (William George), 1884-1959, 1938–1939 (Box 131, Folder 6)
    - Summerson, John, 1904-1992, 1953–1957 (Box 131, Folder 7)
    - Sundheim, Herman L., 1978 (Box 131, Folder 8)
    - Sussler, Frank and Joan, 1969–1978 (Box 131, Folder 9)
    - Sutherland, Lucy Stuart, Dame, 1975 (Box 131, Folder 10)
    - Sutro Library, 1952–1969 (Box 131, Folder 11)
    - Swager, Beverley R., 1948 (Box 131, Folder 12)
    - Swan, Bradford F. (Bradford Fuller), 1947–1964 (Box 131, Folder 13)
      Letters from Lewis to Swan, the gift of Stephen Parks in 1989, were interfiled in 2018.
    - Swan, Joseph R., 1937–1966 (Box 131, Folder 14)
    - Swan, Nathalie Henderson, 1960–1965 (Box 131, Folder 15)
    - Swan, Thomas W. (Thomas Walter), 1877-1975, 1957–1963 (Box 131, Folder 16)
    - Swann, Arthur, 1875-1959, 1936–1973 (Box 131, Folder 17)
    - Swiggett, Howard, 1891-1957, 1951–1952 (Box 131, Folder 18)
    - Symington, James McKim, 1967–1978 (Box 131, Folder 19)
    - Szechenyi, Gladys Vanderbilt, Countess, 1887-1965, 1948–1956 (Box 132, Folder 1)
    - Ta-Tz, general (Box 132, Folder 2-4)
    - Taft, Charles P. (Charles Phelps), 1897-1983, 1938–1973 (Box 132, Folder 5)
    - Taft, Robert A. (Robert Alphonso), 1889-1953, 1937–1953 (Box 132, Folder 6)
    - Taft, William Howard, 1915-1991, 1955 (Box 132, Folder 7)
    - Tait, George, II, 1947–1952 (Box 132, Folder 8)
    - Tait, J. A., 1953–1954 (Box 132, Folder 9)
    - Talbot, Milo and Rose, 1953–1967 (Box 132, Folder 10)
    - Tallmadge, Abby, 1948–1950 (Box 132, Folder 11)
    - Tanis, James, 1928-2015, and Florence B., 1964–1978 (Box 132, Folder 12)
    - Tapp, E. J. (Edwin John), 1948–1961 (Box 132, Folder 13)
    - Tarkington, Booth, 1869-1946, 1938 (Box 132, Folder 14)
    - Tate Gallery, 1969–1971 (Box 132, Folder 15)
    - Tavern Club (Boston, Mass.), 1956–1960 (Box 132, Folder 16)
    - Taylor, A. I. P., 1954–1955 (Box 132, Folder 17)
    - Taylor, Donald S., 1924-, 1951–1961 (Box 132, Folder 18)
    - Taylor, Francis Henry, 1903-1957, 1951–1953 (Box 132, Folder 19)
    - Taylor, Henry C. (Henry Calhoun), 1894-1971, and Jeannette, 1933–1968 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Taylor, Robert H., 1950–1974 (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - Taylor, Samuel S. B., 1968–1978 (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Tenney, Daniel G., 1953–1961 (Box 133, Folder 4)
    - Thacher, Anson S. and Margaret, 1968–1977 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Thacher, Sherman Day, 1861-1931, 1914-1917 (Box 133, Folder 17)
      The folder contains three letters: one from Miranda Lewis to Thacher about Wilmarth Lewis and his horse (1914), one from Wilmarth Lewis as a Yale student to Thacher (1915), and one from Thacher to Wilmarth Lewis (1917).
    - Thacher, Thomas D., Sr. and Jr., 1937–1959 (Box 133, Folder 6)
    - Thames and Hudson, 1963–1978 (Box 133, Folder 7)
    - Thane, Elswyth, 1900-1984, 1968–1969 (Box 133, Folder 8)
    - Thieme, Evelyn, 1947 (Box 133, Folder 9)
    - Thos. Agnew and Sons Ltd., 1948–1978 (Box 133, Folder 10-11)
    - Thomas J. Gannon, Inc., 1939–1959 (Box 133, Folder 12)
    - Thomas Thorp (Firm), 1925–1972 (Box 133, Folder 13)
    - Thompson, Edmund, 1897-1974, 1930–1964 (Box 133, Folder 14)
    - Thompson's Book Shop, 1950–1951 (Box 133, Folder 15)
    - Thoms, Herbert, 1885-1972, and Edith C., 1946–1965 (Box 133, Folder 16)
    - Thomson, Gladys Scott, 1935–1956 (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Thomson, James C., Jr., 1952–1958 (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Thorkelin, Frederick, 1958 (Box 134, Folder 3)
    - Thornton, Hugh and May L. M., 1948–1962 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Thorton Wilder Memorial Lecture Fund, 1978–1979 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Tice and Lynch (Customs Brokers), 1944–1951 (Box 134, Folder 6)
    - Tierney, James E., 1974–1978 (Box 134, Folder 7)
    - Tighe, Laurence G., 1938–1957 (Box 134, Folder 8)
    - Times (London, England), 1948–1955 (Box 134, Folder 9)
    - Timlow, Emily, 1968 (Box 134, Folder 10)
    - Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, 1876-1963, 1923–1963 (Box 134, Folder 11)
    - Todd, William B. (William Burton), 1958–1965 (Box 134, Folder 12)
    - Toledo Museum of Art, 1935–1951 (Box 134, Folder 13)
    - Toner, Albert, 1944–1960 (Box 134, Folder 14)
    - Touro Synagogue (Newport, R.I.), 1952 (Box 134, Folder 15)
    - Townsend-Johnson, Pamela, 1928–1975 (Box 134, Folder 16)
    - Townshend, Henry H., 1938–1939 (Box 135, Folder 1)
    - Toynbee, Paget Jackson, 1855-1932, 1926–1930 (Box 135, Folder 2)
      Also present is a letter (1927) from Charles Scott to Toynbee, sent as an enclosure in Toynbee's letter to Lewis (1929), regarding a portrait of George Montagu.
    - Traver, Hope, 1947–1949 (Box 135, Folder 3)
    - Trippe, J. T. (Juan Terry), 1899-1981, 1944–1971 (Box 135, Folder 4)
    - Troide, Lars E., 1942-, 1964–1979 (Box 135, Folder 5-7)
    - Truslove & Hanson, 1955–1975 (Box 135, Folder 8)
    - Tuckerman, Nancy, 1962–1972 (Box 135, Folder 9)
    - Tuckerman, Roger and Betty, 1963–1967 (Box 135, Folder 10)
    - Tunnard, Christopher, 1946–1975 (Box 135, Folder 11)
    - Tunstall, Brian, 1900-1970, 1937–1950 (Box 135, Folder 12)
    - Turck, Hill & Co., Inc., 1946–1947 (Box 135, Folder 13)
    - Tuttle, Day, 1960–1979 (Box 136, Folder 1)
    - Tuttle, H. E. (Henry Emerson), 1890-1946, 1936–1973 (Box 136, Folder 2)
    - Tuve, Rosemond, 1903-1964, 1933–1979 (Box 136, Folder 3)
    - Tweedy, Mary Johnson, 1963–1964 (Box 136, Folder 4)
    - Twickenham (London, England) Municipal Offices, 1934–1962 (Box 136, Folder 5)
    - Twickenham (London, England) Public Libraries, 1934–1963 (Box 136, Folder 6)
    - Tyrrell, Elizabeth, 1955–1975 (Box 136, Folder 7)
    - Ua-Uz, general (Box 136, Folder 8)
    - Uhlman, Diana, 1912-1999, 1958 (Box 136, Folder 9)
    - United States. Bureau of Customs, 1955–1970 (Box 136, Folder 10)
    - United States. National Historical Publications Commission, 1963–1965 (Box 136, Folder 11)
    - United States. National Park Service, 1961 (Box 136, Folder 12)
    - University Club, 1941–1969 (Box 136, Folder 13)
    - U.S. Atomic Energy Commission, 1965 (Box 136, Folder 14)
    - University Microfilms, 1947–1962 (Box 136, Folder 15)
    - University of Chicago, 1936–1974 (Box 136, Folder 16)
    - University of Chicago. Oriental Institute. Museum, 1944–1973 (Box 136, Folder 17)
    - University of Delaware. Library, 1958–1967 (Box 136, Folder 18)
    - University of Glasgow, 1957–1977 (Box 137, Folder 1)
    - University of Illinois at Chicago Circle, 1969–1970 (Box 137, Folder 2)
    - University of Illinois. Library, 1946–1973 (Box 137, Folder 3)
    - University of Liverpool. Library, 1958–1973 (Box 137, Folder 4)
    - University of Michigan, 1934–1969 (Box 137, Folder 5)
    - University of Minnesota. Press, 1973–1974 (Box 137, Folder 6)
    - University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, 1971–1977 (Box 137, Folder 7)
    - University of Oklahoma. Press, 1964–1965 (Box 137, Folder 8)
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1948–1973 (Box 137, Folder 9)
    - University of Reading. Library, 1973 (Box 137, Folder 10)
    - University of San Francisco, 1968–1979 (Box 137, Folder 11-14)
    - University of Toronto, 1970–1979 (Box 138, Folder 1)
    - University of Virginia, 1965–1973 (Box 138, Folder 2)
    - University of Washington, 1967 (Box 138, Folder 3)
    - Va-Vz, general (Box 138, Folder 4)
    - Vail, Thomas, 1926-, and Iris W. Jennings, 1967–1971 (Box 138, Folder 5)
    - Vail, R. W. G. (Robert William Glenroie), 1890-1966, 1954–1957 (Box 138, Folder 6)
    - Vaill, George D., 1939–1973 (Box 138, Folder 7)
    - Valentine, Alan Chester, 1901-, 1937–1965 (Box 138, Folder 8)
    - Van Cleef, Joy, 1974–1978 (Box 138, Folder 9)
    - Vancouver Public Library, 1951–1973 (Box 138, Folder 10)
    - Vanderbilt, Paul, 1954 (Box 138, Folder 11)
    - Van Devanter, Willis, 1965–1970 (Box 138, Folder 12)
    - Van de Velde, R., 1945–1946 (Box 138, Folder 13)
    - Van Dusen, Henry P., 1951–1955 (Box 138, Folder 14)
    - Van Marx, Alla, 1940–1941 (Box 138, Folder 15)
    - Van Patten, Nathan, 1887-, 1949–1951 (Box 138, Folder 16)
    - Van Ravenswaay, Charles, 1965–1976 (Box 138, Folder 17)
    - Van Santvoord, Charles, 1938–1967 (Box 138, Folder 18)
    - Van Thal, Herbert, 1904-1983, 1959 (Box 139, Folder 1)
    - Van Winkle, Kingland, 1967–1970 (Box 139, Folder 2)
    - Varma, Devendra P., 1923-, 1955–1979 (Box 139, Folder 3)
    - Vernon, Dorothy, 1935–1964 (Box 139, Folder 4)
    - Victoria and Albert Museum, 1920–1978 (Box 139, Folder 5)
    - Vietor, Alexander O., 1944–1978 (Box 139, Folder 6)
    - Vincent, George F., 1940 (Box 139, Folder 7)
    - Vincent-Smith, Margaret, 1948 (Box 139, Folder 8)
    - Vinogradoff, Igor, 1901-1987, and Julian, 1963 (Box 139, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Historical Society, 1953–1967 (Box 139, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1949–1967 (Box 139, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Quarterly Review, 1945–1965 (Box 139, Folder 12)
    - Von Holt, Herman V., 1972–1979 (Box 139, Folder 13)
    - Vose Galleries of Boston, 1947–1964 (Box 139, Folder 14)
    - Wa, general (Box 139, Folder 15)
    - We-Wz, general (Box 140, Folder 1-4)
    - W. & G. Foyle Ltd., 1937–1957 (Box 140, Folder 5)
    - W. Heffer & Sons, 1937–1962 (Box 140, Folder 6)
    - Wadsworth Atheneum, 1936–1978 (Box 140, Folder 7)
    - Wagner, Anthony R., 1935–1965 (Box 140, Folder 8)
    - Wagner, Henry R. (Henry Raup), 1862-1957, 1946 (Box 141, Folder 1)
    - Wainwright, Nicholas B., 1968–1977 (Box 141, Folder 2)
    - Waldegrave, Geoffrey Noel, Earl, 1905-1995, and Mary, 1930–1979 (Box 141, Folder 3-6)
      Also present is a transcript of a letter from Vera Grenfell to her sister Mary Waldegrave, written from London, on October 5, 1940, and Lewis's typed notes on the Walpole collection at Chewton made as of August 3, 1974.
    - Waldegrave, William Arthur, 1963 (Box 141, Folder 7)
    - Walker, Charles A. (Charles Allen), 1914-, 1965–1966 (Box 141, Folder 8)
    - Walker, Hugh, 1914-, 1979 (Box 141, Folder 9)
    - Walker, John, 1944–1972 (Box 141, Folder 10)
    - Wallace, A. Dayle, 1933–1973 (Box 142, Folder 1-4)
    - Wallace, Edward B., 1949–1962 (Box 142, Folder 5)
    - Wallace, George J., 1967–1971 (Box 142, Folder 6)
    - Waller, Sir Wathen, 1932–1959 (Box 142, Folder 7)
    - Walpole, Angel, 1947–1952 (Box 142, Folder 8)
    - Walpole, Dorothea Frances Montgomerie and Robert Henry, 1931–1961 (Box 143, Folder 1)
    - Walpole Society (Great Britain), 1934–1979 (Box 143, Folder 2)
    - Walpole Society (U.S.)
      - Correspondence and ephemera, 1951–1974 (Box 143, Folder 3-6)
      - Correspondence and ephemera, 1975–1979 (Box 144, Folder 1-2)
      - Correspondence related to Farmington meeting, 1967 (Box 144, Folder 3)
    - Walsdorf, John J., 1963–1976 (Box 144, Folder 4)
    - Walter T. Spencer (Firm), 1924–1969 (Box 144, Folder 5)
    - Walters Art Gallery (Baltimore, Md.), 1944–1978 (Box 144, Folder 6)
    - Wand, Martin, 1979 (Box 144, Folder 7)
    - Wang, Arthur W., 1966 (Box 144, Folder 8)
    - Warburg, James P. (James Paul), 1896-1969, 1937–1950 (Box 144, Folder 9)
    - Ward, Caroline Bush, -1962, 1952–1962 (Box 144, Folder 10)
    - Wardwell, Allen, 1873-1953, 1940–1946 (Box 144, Folder 11)
    - Wardwell, Edward, 1958–1960 (Box 144, Folder 12)
    - Waring, James J., 1883-1962, 1939–1941 (Box 144, Folder 13)
    - Warner, Alden Y., III, 1977–1979 (Box 144, Folder 14)
    - Warren, Edward W. and Rhoda, 1958–1978 (Box 145, Folder 1)
    - Washington Cathedral. Rare Book Library, 1966–1973 (Box 145, Folder 2)
    - Wasserman, Earl R. (Earl Reeves), 1913-, 1938 (Box 145, Folder 3)
    - Wasson, R. Gordon (Robert Gordon), 1898-1986, 1956 (Box 145, Folder 4)
    - Watson, A. John, 1934–1979 (Box 145, Folder 5-6)
      A. J. Watson donated to the library in 1983 the letters he had received from Lewis.
    - Watson, F. J. B. (Francis John Bagott), 1907-1992, 1937–1979 (Box 145, Folder 7-8)
    - Watson, George, 1953–1967 (Box 145, Folder 9)
    - Watson, Rowland, 1962–1963 (Box 145, Folder 10)
    - Waverly, Ava Anderson, 1896-1974, 1955 (Box 146, Folder 1)
    - Wead, Eunice, 1946–1956 (Box 146, Folder 2)
    - Weaver, Howard Sayre, 1963–1964 (Box 146, Folder 3)
    - Webb, J. Watson (James Watson), 1884-1960, 1941–1957 (Box 146, Folder 4)
    - Webb, Vanderbilt, 1891-1956, 1935–1938 (Box 146, Folder 5)
    - Wedgwood, C. V. (Cicely Veronica), 1910-1997, 1958–1971 (Box 146, Folder 6)
    - Weed, Lewis H. (Lewis Hill), 1886-1952, 1947–1950 (Box 146, Folder 7)
    - Weeks, Edward, 1898-1989, 1944–1975 (Box 146, Folder 8)
    - Weigle, Luther A. (Luther Allan), 1880-1976, 1946 (Box 146, Folder 9)
    - Weimerskirch, Philip John, 1967–1979 (Box 146, Folder 10)
    - Weir, Andrew and Rosalie, 1971–1976 (Box 146, Folder 11)
    - Wellcome Historical Medical Library, 1951–1963 (Box 146, Folder 12)
    - Wellek, René, 1975–1977 (Box 146, Folder 13)
    - Welles, Roger P., 1962 (Box 146, Folder 14)
    - Wells, Gabriel, 1862-1946, 1936–1939 (Box 146, Folder 15)
    - Wells, James M., 1948–1968 (Box 146, Folder 16)
    - Welsh, Elysabeth, 1962–1969 (Box 146, Folder 17)
    - Wenner, John, 1963 (Box 146, Folder 18)
    - Werner, Arno, 1899-1995, 1953–1965 (Box 146, Folder 19)
    - Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.), 1966–1970 (Box 146, Folder 20)
    - Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.). Library, 1972–1974 (Box 146, Folder 21)
    - Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.). Press, 1969–1970 (Box 146, Folder 22)
    - Wessells, Helen E. (Helen Elizabeth), 1903-, 1947 (Box 146, Folder 23)
    - West, Audrey, 1952 (Box 147, Folder 1)